Guide to the Dept. of Slavic and Eurasian Studies records, 1956-1983
Duke University. University Archives
Dept. of Slavic and Eurasian Studies records 1956-1983
Duke University. University Archives
Duke University. Dept. of Slavic and Eurasian Studies.
4.5 linear feet Extent: 3000 Items
Courses in Russian language and literature were offered at Duke University in the early 1950s. The Russian Department was formed in 1958, renamed Slavic Languages and Literatures in 1967, and renamed again in the 2006-2007 academic year to Slavic and Eurasian Studies. Collection contains largely the files of Magnus Jan Krynski, chairman of the department from ca. 1966-1988, along with the records of other faculty members. The material dates from 1956-1983.
uaslavic
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Provenance
The Dept. of Slavic and Eurasian Studies records were received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1990.
Historical Note
Courses in Russian language and literature were offered at Duke University in the early 1950s. The Russian Department was formed in 1958, and renamed Slavic Languages and Literatures in 1967. Bronislas Jezierski was the first chairman (1958-1966), followed by Magnus Krynski (1966-1989), Tom Lahusen (1989-1994), Stefan Pugh (1995-1998), Denis Mickiewicz (Acting Director, 1998-1999), and Edna Andrews (2000-). The name of the department changed to Slavic and Eurasian Studies in the 2006-2007 academic year.
Collection Overview
Collection contains largely the files of Magnus Jan Krynski, chairman of the department from ca. 1966-1988, along with the records of other faculty members. Materials present include correspondence with students, job applicants, and faculty at other institutions, departmental budgets, vitae, printed matter, reports, and other materials pertaining to the teaching of Slavic languages and literatures, including courses in technical Russian for scientists and engineers, and professional activities of the faculty. The material dates from 1956-1983.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University -- History -- 20th century.; Duke University. Dept. of Slavic Languages and Literatures.; Duke University. Faculty.; Slavic Studies.
Related Material
Interdisciplinary Studies Records, 1998-2006
University Archives. Duke University.
Knight (Douglas M.) Records, 1949-1970
University Archives. Duke University.
News Service Biographical Files, 1960-2004
University Archives. Duke University.
Photograph Collection, 1861-2006
University Archives. Duke University.
Pye (A. Kenneth), Chancellor, Records and Papers, 1960-1983
University Archives. Duke University.
Sanford (Terry) Records and Papers, 1945-1998
University Archives. Duke University.
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records, 1934-
University Archives. Duke University.
Wladyslaw W. Kulski Papers, 1710-1989 (bulk 1933-1969).
University Archives. Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Container List, 3 Box
  - Course Lists, Middlebury, c. 1958? (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Students, 1980-1982
  - Correspondence with Students, 1980-1982
  - Course Publicity, 1981
  - Counseling Service, Placement Tests, 1970-1971
  - Credit Union, 1968-1971
  - Course Flyers, 1981, 1983
  - Departmental Memos (Meeting Minutes, Faculty Correspondence), 1982
  - Miscellaneous Academic Memos, 1982-1983
  - Accounting Operations (General Info), 1982
  - Books Available in NY Public Library, 1974-1978
  - Books Ordered for Spring 1979
  - Book Ordering, 1981
  - Accounting (General Information), 1983
  - Chronicle Correspondence, 1982
  - Computerization of Language Oriented Enterprises (COLOE), 1982
  - Comparative Literature Correspondence, 1978
  - Peter McClintock, Curriculum Vita, 1968
  - Census, 1976-1979
  - Census, Fall 1981 and Spring 1982, 1981-1982
  - American Association of University Professors (AAUP), 1967-1968
  - American Association of Teachers of Slavic and East European Languages (AATSEEL); American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies (AASS), 1967-1972
  - Campus Politics, 1968-1969
  - Computer Program and Russian Committee, 1967-1970
  - Department Name, 1966-1967
  - Academic Guide for Freshmen, 1968-1971
  - Early Duke - UNC Co-op Correspondence; Dwivedi, D.S., 1966-1971
  - Edgerton, William B. Correspondence, 1969-1970
  - Enrollment Figures in Southern Schools, ETS Exams, 1966
  - Gasinski, Tadeusz (UNC Dept of Linguistics), Correspondence, 1966-1968
  - Graduate School Requests and Graduate Bulletin, 1966-1968
  - Lerner, Warren (Chairman's Correspondence), 1967-1970
  - Honors Program and Old Lectures, 1965-1969
  - Old Library, 1967-1971
  - Miscellany (Inquiries and Memos), 1965-1971
  - Summer School Business, 1980-1981
  - Syllabi and Calendar, 1981
  - Publications, Faculty, 1970
  - Independent Study (Statement, Application), undated
  - Interoffice Memos, 1981-1982
  - Language Lab Tapes (Correspondence Regarding), 1981
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence, 1981
  - Spring 1982 Scheduling and Registration, 1982
  - Spring 1982 Jezierski Syllabi and Exam Outlines, 1982
  - Promotions at Duke (Search for President), 1969
  - Personnel Policies, 1967-1971
  - Polish Periodicals, Complete Sets, Library, 1969-1971
  - Princeton - Cooperative Program in Critical Languages, 1967-1968
  - Publicity, Miscellaneous, 1966-1970
  - Reference Books and Directories (Kept in Krynski's Office), 1966
  - Registration Figures, 1960-1968
  - Research Council (Faculty), 1965-1969
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools (S.A.C.S.), 1963-1965
  - Southern Conference on Slavic Studies (S.C.O.S.S.), 1968-1970
  - Summer Session Correspondence, 1967-1971
  - Symposium Committee, 1966
  - Teacher Education Guidelines (State of N.C.), 1968
  - Textbook Orders, 1966-1967
  - Ullrich, Helen (Correspondence), 1969
  - UNC Department of Linguistics (Slavic and Oriental Languages), 1967-1969
  - Undergraduate Instruction, 1965
  - Course Approval Forms, Undergraduate, 1970-1975 (Box 2)
  - Courses Pending, 1975
  - Courses Drop / Add Approved, 1974-1979
  - Committee on Russian Studies, 1971-1976
  - American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies (AAASS) - Ohio State Planning Conference, 1971-1972
  - University Business (Other than UFCAs and Academic Council)
  - Southern Conference on Slavic Studies (S.C.O.S.S.) - Miami, 1972
  - Southern Conference on Slavic Studies (S.C.O.S.S.) - UNC / Duke (Correspondence), 1971
  - Southern Conference on Slavic Studies (S.C.O.S.S.) - Raleigh, 1973 Scientific Russian Course, 1971-1972
  - Films (Correspondence), 1970
  - Films (Polish), 1975
  - Program II, 1972-1974
  - Foster, Ludmila (Correspondence re: Denver Conference), 1970-1973
  - Folejewski, Zkigniew (Correspondence re: Plish Scholars Conference), 1975
  - Department Business Correspondence, 1971-1975
  - Prof. Treml Interview in Durham Sun, 1974
  - Freshman Advisees, 1971-1973
  - Departmental Business, 1979
  - Reading Lists, Exam Samples, undated
  - Reading Lists, Miscellaneous, undated
  - Graduate Education - Assessment of Quality
  - M.A. Program (Correspondence), 1969-1970
  - M.A. Program - Course Approvals, 1966-1967 (2 folders)
  - Career Opportunities in Russian
  - M.A. Program - Submissions for Course Approval, 1966
  - Pavlov, Hilda, 1969-1971
  - Secretary Correspondence, 1969
  - Aronson's Article on Teaching Russian Vocabulary, undated
  - Budget Statements, 1956-1965
  - PL 480 - Program for Poland, 1972-1974
  - NDEA Fellowships, 1967
  - National Association of Self-Instruction Language Programs, 1973
  - Miscellaneous Faculty Correspondence, 1972-1977
  - Musica Moderna Polorum, 1976
  - Mrozek, S. (Correspondence, Clippings), 1971-1979
  - Moser, Charles (Correspondence), 1966-1972
  - Moscow Trip, 1971
  - Mihailovich, Vasa (Correspondence), 1970-1975
  - MLA Faculty Exchange Program, 1972-1975
  - Majors - Revised Requirements, 1969-1973
  - Letters to Majors, etc., 1966-1974
  - Polish Journal, 1977-1978
  - Departmental Business, 1982 (Box 3)
  - Internship Information, 1982
  - International Research and Exchange Board (IREX), 1980-1983
  - Jezierski, Bronislas - Correspondence, 1983
  - Kosciuszko Foundation, 1982
  - Kosciuszko Foundation Grants, 1982
  - Krynski Published, 1982
  - Krynski, Letters to, 1979-1983
  - Krynski, C.V., (3 folders)
  - McGuire - Correspondence Re: Translation, 1975-1982
  - National Security Agency (NSA) Correspondence, 1983
  - Pol 12, Spring Exam, 1983
  - Research Council, Forms and Information, 1979-1982
  - Pol 11, 1982
  - University Business (Councils, Arts and Sciences), 1982
  - University Business, 1982
  - University Business, 1983
  - University of California Press, Milosz's Book, 1982
  - Very Important Letters, 1975
  - Honors Program, 1970
  - Instytut Badan Literackich (IBL), 1973-1975
  - International Studies, 1973
  - International Research and Exchange Board (IREX), 1970-1975
  - Jezierski, Bronislas - Correspondence, 1969-1980
  - Kosciuszko Foundation - Correspondence and Newsletters, 1970-1977
  - Kosciuszko Foundation - Newsletters, 1978
  - Krynski, Private Business Correspondence, 1976
  - Krynski, Personal Correspondence, 1967-1972
  - Krzyzanowski, Jerzy, 1971-1973
  - Krynski, New Courses, 1975
  - Perkins Library, 1976-1978
  - Language Lab, Procedure for Scheduling Film Programs
  - Language Lab, Correspondence, 1970-1973
  - Lecturers, Visiting, 1971-1972
  - Maguire, Robert - Correspondence, 1967-1972
  - M.A.T. Programs, c. 1969?
  - M.A. Brochure, 1966-1972
  - Budget, 1978-1979
  - Budget, 1977-1978
  - Budget, 1975-1976
  - Budget, 1973-1974
  - Budget, 1971-1972
  - University Centers for Rational Alternatives (UCRA), 1970-1980
  - Undergraduate Bulletin, 1970
  - Teacher Evaluation, 1970-1974
  - Comparative Literature Committee, 1972-1975
  - Committee on International Studies, 1967-1971
  - Class Schedules, 1970-1971
  - Admissions Office, Program Materials, 1975
  - Books Ordered from Perguson, 1970-1978
  - Course History, 1966-1967
  - Course Offerings, 1970-1973
  - Bevan, William - Correspondence, 1979
  - Baer, Joachim, 1975-1976